

□ (+591) 76475229 | Sangel.zenteno.u@gmail.com | OangelUrg | https://angelurg.github.io/portfolio/

Summary_

The incredible pace of research and new discoveries in artificial intelligence points to a very exciting future. Researchers are making great advances towards achieving human-level intelligence in computers. As a computer science research assistant, I am passionate about advancing the current state of the art. I am ready to take the next step and continue developing my skills by pursuing a master's degree.

Education

UPB(Universidad Privada Boliviana)

Cochabamba, Bolivia

Feb. 2017 - Jul. 2021

B.S. IN COMPUTER SYSTEMS ENGINEERING

- · Graduated with honors, Summa Cum Laude.
- CGPA 93.5/100

Experience_

CINTI - Research Center for New Computer Technologies - UPB (Universidad Privada **Boliviana**)

Cochabamba, Bolivia

RESEARCH ASSISTANT Jun. 2021 - Present

- · Data collection, processing, and implementation of a recurrent neural network for automatic spectrometer calibration using TensorFlow.
- · Data collection, processing, and implementation of a convolutional neural network for automatic detection of chemical elements with Tensor-Flow. Fine-tuned an EfficientDet model.
- Implementation of a spectrometry application for mobile phones using Flutter and deployment of TensorFlow Lite models.
- · Implementation of a spectrometry application for Raspberry Pi using Python and OpenCV for image processing.
- Development of a distributed GitHub scrapper used to massively retrieve and analyze open source code repositories using NodeJS and MQTT.
- Development of a REST API using Django for a spectrometry remote lab, this allows users to visualize the experiments with a web camera, manipulate remotely the spectrometer, and collect spectral data.
- Development of a REST API using Django for a remote laboratory booking system, allowing users to book and manage appointments for various types of experiments and tests, including spectrometry. The API allows users to view available time slots, reserve a slot, and manage their appointments. Open Source project.

Truextend Cochabamba, Bolivia

SOFTWARE ENGINEER INTERN

Jul. 2020 - Aug. 2020

- Deployment of internal applications using Docker and GitLab CI/CD.
- Implementation of animations using Angular and SASS.
- Updating internal documentation on how to run the apps and services.

Publications

CINTI - Research Center for New Computer Technologies

- Zenteno, A., Orellana, A., Villazon, A., Ormachea, O. (2023). Automatic Selection of Reference Lines for Spectrometer Calibration with Recurrent Neural Networks, SmartTech-IC 2022.
- Ormachea, O., Villazon, A., Orellana, A., Zenteno, A. (2023). A low-cost 3D-printed spectrometer based on Raspberry Pi, RIAO/OPTILAS. (Preprint)
- Villazon, A., Ormachea, O., Orellana, A., Zenteno, A., Fransson T. (2023). Work in Progress: A Booking System for Remote Laboratories The EXPLORE Energy Digital Academy (EEDA) case study, REV2023 Conference.
- Villazon, A., Ormachea, O., Zenteno, A., Orellana, A. (2023). A Low-Cost Spectrometry Remote Laboratory. In: Auer, M.E., El-Seoud, S.A., Karam, O.H. (eds) Artificial Intelligence and Online Engineering. REV 2022. Lecture Notes in Networks and Systems, vol 524. Springer, Cham.
- Rosales E., Rosa A., Basso M., Villazon, A., Orellana, A., Zenteno, A., et al (2022). Characterizing Java Streams in the Wild, 26th International Conference on Engineering of Complex Computer Systems (ICECCS).

Projects

NASA SPACE APPS CHALLENGE

• Development of a web platform to explore papers published by NASA, we used a large language model to summarize more than 300.000 papers. Implemented a semantic search engine converting summaries into embeddings. These were also used to visualize papers as a connected graph. Winning project.

"DIVE INTO READING" HACKATHON

· Development of a virtual reality video game to encourage reading, we used language models to generate quizzes of any book. Finalist project.

LOGO DIFFUSION

• The prototype aims to fine-tune Stable Diffusion models to create high-quality logos by training them on a dataset of logos and adjusting their parameters to produce unique logos.

CHAR-RNN

• Character-level language model for text-based data. Char-RNN takes in a sequence of characters as input and attempts to generate a sequence of characters as output. It is designed to be used as a template for building and training Char-RNN models for various types of text-based data.

Honors & Awards

- Winner, NASA Space Apps Challenge Bolivia. Challenge "Can AI preserve our science legacy?" 2022
- 2022 Finalist, "Dive into Reading" Hackathon, organized by the Embassy of the United States in Bolivia.
- Winner, graduation with honors, Summa Cum Laude. 2021
- 2021 Winner, excellence scholarship, granted to top 3 best students in the engineering faculty.
- 2020 Winner, honor roll.
- 2019 Winner, honor roll.
- 2018 Winner, honor roll.
- Winner, a 50% scholarship granted by UPB to the top-performing students in a math and verbal reasoning 2017 exam.

Certificates and Additional Courses

Machine Learning - CS229

Online

STANFORD ONLINE - FREE

· Fundamentals of machine learning, including supervised and unsupervised learning, neural networks, support vector machines, reinforcement learning, and adaptive control.

Deep Learning - CS230 Online

Coursera

Oct. 2022

· Learned about the fundamentals of deep learning including neural networks, convolutional neural networks, recurrent neural networks, and transformers

Natural Language Processing with Deep Learning - CS224n

Online

STANFORD ONLINE - FREE

Mar. 2023

• The course covers the basic concepts and ideas in Natural Language Processing. Start with word-level and syntactic processing and move on to question answering, and machine translation. Finally, apply a complex neural network model to a large-scale NLP problem for final project.

Deep Reinforcement Learning Course

Online Mar 2023

Deep Reinforcement Learning (Deep RL) with well-known libraries such as Stable Baselines3, RL Baselines3 Zoo, Sample Factory, and CleanRL.

Design and 3D printing Online

UPB

Feb. 2023

• Design with Fusion 360 and 3D slicing with Ultimaker Cura

Extracurricular Activity _____

Ada in Data South America

WEBINAR AND INTERNAL TRAINING

Dec. 2022 - Present

- · Planning informative webinars that cover a wide range of data topics, including the Hugging Face transformers library.
- Designing training materials and presentations, including research papers.
- · Facilitating internal training sessions on Transformers, with a focus on their practical use in the field.

Skills_

Python, SQL, git, sklearn, NumPy, Pandas, PyTorch, TensorFlow, Django, Flutter, MQTT and Docker.

Languages _____

English C1 - advanced: TOEFL score 106 / 120

Spanish Native